Eyasu Bekele

eyasubekele@cmail.carleton.ca | (613) 400 8419

1522 Beaverpond Dr, Ottawa, ON | K1B3R9

www.eyasubekele.com

SUMMARY

A recent graduate with a bachelor's degree in Architectural Conservation and Sustainability Engineering, Structural stream, and a minor in Business. I am a quick learner and passionate about solving unique engineering problems. Experienced in structural design and analysis, AutoCAD, Revit, SAP2000 and similar software tools.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - Architectural Conservation and Sustainability Structural Stream, Minor – Business

2014-2019

• CGPA (3.3/4), Recipient of: Entrance Scholarship

Core Major Courses:

Structural Analysis I & II
Streel, Concrete, Wood Design
Project Management
GIS, Surveying and Graphics
Green Building Design
Architectural Technology I, II, III, V
Fire Safety

Core Minor Courses:

Business Marketing Financial Management Financial Accounting Information Systems Organizational Behaviour Business Law

RELEVANT SKILLS

Technical Engineering and Business Skills

- High level knowledge of AutoCAD, IntelliCAD, PTC Creo, and Revit proficiency and the ability to participate in the production of full set of architectural design
- Academic background in project management, project cost estimation, and scheduling
- Ability to use steel, concrete, and wood design handbooks for structural applications and perform design calculations
- Capable of using eQUEST, Hot 2000, and THERM energy modeling software obtained through applied projects
- Familiar with SAP2000, structural analysis and design software, gained through applied projects
- Strong knowledge of Total Station, and 3D Laser Scanner used for heritage site recording and surveying purposes
- Applied knowledge of website coding using HTML, CSS, and Java Script obtained through developing a
 personal website
- Familiar with Matlab, Sketch-up, and Minitab gained through academic labs
- Microsoft Office, Excel, Access, Word, and Power Point
- Well trained and certified in Workplace Health and Safety Hazard (WHSH)

Leadership and Communication Skills

- Led a Reverse Engineering project by providing project schedule and assigning tasks to members with deadlines to complete project ahead of time
- Successfully completed CCDP course (Communication skills for engineering students) which reinforced ability to write technical reports

APPLIED PROJECT

Structural Frame Design

Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

- Used hand calculations to find supporting reactions and internal forces of the frame
- Analyzed the 3D dimensional two-bay two story braced frame using SAP2000

Site Development Sep 2016 – Dec 2016

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

- Applied the Canada building code and produced a full-scale design using AutoCAD
- Conducted numbers of research to minimize the total expense of the proposed building
- Worked attentively with teammates to produce professional proposal that meets the city's requirement

Developing a Net-Zero Building

Sep 2018 – Apr 2019

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

- Responsible for the design of an 8-storey net-zero office building located in 529 Richmond Road, Ottawa
- As part of multidisciplinary team of engineers, prepared Gantt charts, work beak down structure and precedence diagrams to ensure a well-coordinated project within deadlines
- Produced floor plan and BIM design involving material details using Revit and AutoCAD
- Run and analyzed different energy model using eQuest to obtain energy balance
- Wrote multiple technical reports and gave presentations to keep the lead engineers and clients updated about the project progress

WORK EXPERIENCE

Remote CAD Drafter

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Glimpse ArchViz & BIM Studio

- Worked with modifying existing CAD drawings, and material cost analysis
- Designed a 2D floor plan for various residential and office buildings
- Integrated preliminary sketch up drawings with Revit

Tutor Mentor Nov 2016 - Jan 2018

TutorBright, Ottawa, ON

- Helped students establish goals and timelines that break their assignments and projects down into smaller parts
- Assisted students determine what information they will need to study for quizzes or tests and practice answering anticipated questions with them

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Executive Workshop Coordinator

Mar 2015 - Mar 2016

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

- Conducted office administration, sold course packs and prepared documents which increased the work flow
- Planned and organized events which strengthened individual's interest on working in teams

Fall Orientation Facilitator

Aug 2016 - Sep 2016

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

Facilitated brainstorming sessions to create innovative ideas which increased attendance at social events and allowed the program to engage more students